Hey everybody, Brian Gutekunst [music]
joins us from the league meetings in
Brian. For you, what's the most
productive part? The formal meetings or
the informal stuff with your colleagues
from around the league?
>> They're both important, but I think
catching up with with you know,
colleagues throughout the league is
important and you know, and so that's
but it's all important. You know, it's
all all stuff that that we need to be
aware of and you know, a lot of things
that are talked about here, you know,
they'll be continued conversations.
Um it's been a good couple days so far.
Draft coming up in about a month. Where
are you at in that process? We're kind
of in the middle of what we call phase
three and we're in pretty good shape.
[music] We feel really good about where
we are with the board and our guys are
just getting off the road a little bit
now. There's a few pro days left that
they're finishing up. Uh it'll be good
next [music] week to get it back in the
fold and and start going through the all
the things that they've gathered over
the last uh three, four weeks.
At the combine, you said it's all about
everything we do was about winning now.
How good does this draft have to be to
have an impact in that regard? Well,
certainly all these guys that when we
were drafting we're looking at it as a
you know, as a long-term investment. But
we're also all expecting them to play
their role and do their job if called
upon in his early years, you know, so
this class will be like any other, you
know, we're going to ask a lot of them
and we'll be excited to have them.
Whether they come out of the shoots and
have a really good rookie year or
whether maybe it takes them a little bit
of time to become the players that
they're going to become. We're good
either way.
When I ask you about [music] some of the
additions you've already made, just a
quick thumbnail sketch of what attracted
you to them. Javon Hargrave. Yeah.
Obviously a really good player in this
league for a long time, Pro Bowl player.
I really like his all-around [music]
game. He can play the run, he can rush
the passer. He's explosively strong
human being and again, anytime you can
find players in the league that can
affect the passer as well,
um those guys are hard to find. Zaire
Franklin. Obviously a Pro Bowl type
player. He's been a starter at inside
linebacker for six years. Someone who we
had our eye on early when he was a
special teams backup type player. Not
only the player that he is, but the
leadership he brings is something that
really attracted us to him. Benjamin St.
Juste. Length. He's got really good
size. I think he had his best year last
year so far of his young career and we
think his best football is ahead of him.
One more, Skyy Moore. Should add [music]
some juice to the return game, but
possibly more. Yeah. Last year was the
first year where he really had both the
kick and punt return roles exclusively.
Did an excellent job. He's very
explosive, very, very tough to take down
by the first tackler and I do think it's
an offense when once Matt and then when
that staff gets to know him, I think
there will be some opportunities there
as well. Brian, are you especially
excited about the second years for
fellows like Matthew Golden and Anthony
Belton, the big man? Oh yeah, both those
guys and the opportunities that they
were given last year, I think they did
an extraordinary job in year one. And at
the end of the year, I think everybody
could see we probably needed to give
Matthew the ball more because he was
very explosive and and made so many
plays when he did. And Anthony, I just
you know, obviously he was a tackle in
college, we moved him inside. Really
proud of the way he [music] battled
through things and he gives us a little
bit of size and power in there that that
we're looking for. Did you see enough of
Baron Zirrell and Colin Oliver last
season to know what you got in those
players? Certainly Baron, we did we did
a really nice job in the snaps that he
was given and
uh certainly there's going to be a lot
more opportunities for him, I think this
year just with the way our roster starts
to shake out. And then Colin was one of
those players who wasn't sure we were
going to be able to get him onto the
roster to play. As the season went, we
got him in the last [music] game and his
speed showed up in that game, so both
those players are young, promising
players. Best football's going to be
ahead of them.
Uh they're going to get more
opportunities this year. Touchdown!
Touchdown!
You guys played a lot of real good ball
last year, but at the end couldn't
finish games, games you seemingly had in
control. Have you figured that one out
now that you've had a few months to
reflect?
>> Well, I think it's going to be something
that our organization, the team as a
whole figures out as we go into this
season, right? Everything starts anew,
right? And so we we haven't even had a
practice yet, but I do think it's one of
those things we we spend a lot of time
on, but ultimately it's going to be the
work that our players put in with our
coaches that get to that point. And I
think a lot of it too is confidence,
right? You know, a lot of it is is
having the confidence to do that in
those situations, so we're at the very
beginning, nothing started yet,
um but we're excited to get it going.